<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language>
	<entry name="AlienAggression" value="Xenology"/>
	<entry name="AlienAggressionDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;There is no such thing as an 'alien'. There are but different understandings and ways of life, all created and dictated by our Lord. Let us bask in His insight and benevolence.&quot;<br/>    -- Lady Lilith Vermillion, Tempore Dei<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Detention, examination and dissection of native species, combined with investigative neuroscience and genetic research, leads us to better comprehend these enemies and the threat they represent."/>
	<entry name="AlienAggressionProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>-25% alien aggression"/>
	<entry name="Aspidoch" value="Aspidoch Tiling"/>
	<entry name="AspidochDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;We're going to need a bigger... gun.&quot;<br/>    -- Commodore Pequod, First Naval Force.<style name='Default'/><br/><br/> To survive in the high gravity of Pandora, the island-sized Aspidoch seemed impossibly huge. Its bones solved the mystery. A mixture of graphene, buckminster fullerene and carbyne acts as a skeletal structure throughout the great creature, allowing it to deploy its tremendous force without tearing itself apart."/>
	<entry name="AspidochProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Attributes/Power'/> power for heavy units"/>
	<entry name="Assault" value="Operation Valkyrie"/>
	<entry name="AssaultDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;It doesn't matter what you do, as long as you do.&quot;<br/>    -- Admiral James Heid, On War<style name='Default'/><br/><br/> Devised by tactics and logistics experts, Operation Valkyrie is the codename for a large scale reconnaissance operation followed by a massive orbital troop deployment, much like a Blitzkrieg. The result is a swift and powerful strike behind the enemy lines that can decide the outcome of an entire campaign."/>
	<entry name="AssaultProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Provides 3 <icon texture='Operations/ScanIcon' height='16'/> satellite scans on completion<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Provides 3 <icon texture='Operations/DropPodIcon' height='16'/> drop pods on completion"/>
	<entry name="Colonization" value="Colonization Fervor"/>
	<entry name="ColonizationDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;People forget that Pandora isn't like Earth -- it's a SuperTerran planet around a very different star. Yet everything we have was designed for Terran conditions. Even a table leg only operates under certain parameters -- gravity, air pressure, atmospheric acidity, radioactivity, topology and so on -- which are completely different here. And we don't have access to most of our go-to resources. You try building a tank out of fungus!&quot;<br/>    -- Dr. Wendigo, Engineering Department, Togra University.<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The rush for territorial domination on Pandora is relentless. Thankfully, our colonists are irrationally dedicated to the cause, which should give us a headstart in colonization."/>
	<entry name="ColonizationProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Provides a <icon texture='Units/ColonizerIcon' height='16'/> Colonizer on completion<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Provides a <icon texture='Units/TrooperIcon' height='16'/> Colonial Trooper on completion"/>
	<entry name="Construction0" value="Pandoran Construction"/>
	<!-- Robert A. Heinlein, Time Enough for Love ISBN 450-02243-9 / 0-441-81076-4 -->
	<entry name="Construction0Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Cheops' Law: Nothing ever gets built on schedule or within budget.&quot;<br/>    -- Robert A. Heinlein, Time Enough for Love<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>To walk into one of the construction bays is a unique experience. Filling the cavernous hangar is the drone field, an inseparable mass of flying, walking and rolling robots, slaved to the factory's central schematic. From the flitting cutters to the pendulous assembly drones to the lumbering traction engines, it merges into a silver cloud, with a rapidly growing shape at its middle -- the assigned construction project. Enter the cloud and you experience a miracle of the modern age -- the mass splits like a shoal of herring before a predatory shark, while work continues implacably around you.<br/><br/>The construction bay is just one of several new field improvements our architects have designed."/>
	<entry name="Construction0Properties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to construct Construction Bays, Energy Parks, Field Laboratories and Purifiers"/>
	<entry name="Credits" value="Qan Bargaining"/>
	<entry name="CreditsDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;The important thing about a free market is that no exchange takes place unless both parties benefit. Or think they do, at least.&quot;<br/>    -- Abay Qan, The Final Transaction<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Haggling has always been an important part of human commerce, but the Qan have elevated it to an art, using all available market data, down to the seemingly insignificant, to obtain the greatest price advantage. Their technique has always been talked about with high praise, and the easy availability of up-to-the-second data in the modern world greatly facilitates the process."/>
	<entry name="CreditsProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>-25% <icon texture='Resources/Credits'/> purchase costs in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Defense" value="Command Nexus"/>
	<entry name="DefenseDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Once you've acquired power, you need to learn how to focus it.&quot;<br/>    -- Prime Minister Yun Xi, The Large Black Book<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Establishing a centralized command center is a risky move, as its destruction would be disastrous, but it also has its rewards. This headquarters dispatches local tactical information instantaneously and can act as a last-ditch reinforcement, if it is ever needed."/>
	<entry name="DefenseProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Attributes/Power'/> power for units inside your borders"/>
	<entry name="Diplomacy" value="Planetary Council"/>
	<entry name="DiplomacyDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Diplomacy is the art of letting somebody else have your way.&quot;<br/>    -- David Frost<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The establishment of a worldwide diplomatic organization to facilitate cooperation and negotiation between all factions will hopefully boost our reputation and standing. Who says altruism can't also be self-interested?"/>
	<entry name="DiplomacyProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Increases standings with every faction on completion"/>
	<entry name="Ecoform" value="Ecoforming"/>
	<entry name="EcoformDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Transforming the barren lands into fields of green -- fields that extend beyond sight. That will be the planet of our people's dreams.&quot;<br/>    -- Prime Minister Yun Xi, Leadership of the State<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>In the Amazon rain-forest, before it was obliterated, hunter-gatherer tribes would burn out clearings, bring in plants alien to the region, and sculpt the landscape by suppressing hostile flora and fauna. The ecological forming we're doing on Pandora only differs from that in scale. Here, local species are eliminated and the Formers saturate the land with Earth-native minerals (nitrates, phosphates and so on). Then the Formers distribute genetically- and cybernetically-modified Earth plants and pollinating insects that can survive long enough to alter the environment towards the desired norm. "/>
	<entry name="EcoformProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to improve ecoregions<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to worsen ecoregions"/>
	<entry name="FoodMinerals" value="Colony Ship Dismantling"/>
	<entry name="FoodMineralsDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;They broke up the Mayflower too, you know? And the Argo never sailed again -- it just rotted. This old girl has one last chance to be useful. After twenty-seven light years, I think she'd be grateful.&quot;<br/>    -- Foreman Cadenza, Recycling Department, Togra University<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The colony ship used to reach Pandora would take several decades to travel back to our homeworld. So instead of sending it home, we would rather unload all the remaining supplies and then dismantle the whole craft. This will result in a significant one-time resource boost of food and minerals for our new empire."/>
	<entry name="FoodMineralsProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+16 <icon texture='Resources/Food'/> food on completion<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+32 <icon texture='Resources/Minerals'/> minerals on completion"/>
	<entry name="FormerWorkSpeed" value="Great Planetary Survey"/>
	<entry name="FormerWorkSpeedDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;As a great man's influence never ends, so also there is not definite finality, no end, to a great survey; it runs along for centuries, ever responsive to the strain of the increasing needs of a growing population and an enlarging domain.&quot;<br/>    -- Cleveland Abbe<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>This survey will be a comprehensive study of Pandora's ecosystem that greatly improves our understanding of the planet and in turn makes the landscaping process significantly more efficient."/>
	<entry name="FormerWorkSpeedProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>-25% work duration for all Formers"/>
	<entry name="Fungus0" value="Fungus Cultivation"/>
	<entry name="Fungus0Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;I prefer a world covered in fungi to one covered in mushroom clouds.&quot;<br/>    -- Advocate Vivian Gardinier, The Landing Address<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Several of our scientists advocate the theory that the fungus represents some sort of defense system for the planet, since growth and spore dispersal appear to be directly related to the damage done to the environment. The native species like xenomorphs seem largely unaffected by the spores.<br/><br/>Our understanding now reaches far enough that we can safely grow and decompose fungus colonies with our Former units -- though their spores remain just as deadly to other units."/>
	<entry name="Fungus0Properties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Formers suffer no damage in Fungus<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to clear fungus<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to grow fungus"/>
	<entry name="Fungus1" value="Fungus Mutagenesis"/>
	<!-- Shirley Conran, Superwoman  ISBN 0140048790 / 9780140048797 -->
	<entry name="Fungus1Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Life is too short to stuff a mushroom.&quot;<br/>    -- Shirley Conran, Superwoman<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Our latest breakthroughs in the field of genetics have allowed us to alter the characteristics of fungi via PCR site-directed mutagenesis, effectively creating edible plants that can also produce efficient fuel via biomass conversion."/>
	<entry name="Fungus1Properties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+2 <icon texture='Resources/Food'/> food from territories with fungus in all cities<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+2 <icon texture='Resources/Minerals'/> minerals from territories with fungus in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Fungus2" value="Fungal Hormones"/>
	<entry name="Fungus2Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Centuries of Terran herbalism resulted in a few non-toxic mushrooms and a vast array of fungus-derived medicinal compounds. Think what we could do with the infinite varieties of Pandora's mushroom kingdoms.&quot;<br/>    -- Alpheus Schreiber, The Chymical Kitchen<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Genetically-engineered hormones for fungi allow us to effectively double their growth rate and with that their food and mineral output. Highly resistant to hostile climates, diseases, and parasites, mankind's future need for resources might very well be covered just by fungus plantations spanning hundreds of square miles..."/>
	<entry name="Fungus2Properties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+2 <icon texture='Resources/Food'/> food from territories with fungus in all cities<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+2 <icon texture='Resources/Minerals'/> minerals from territories with fungus in all cities"/>
	<entry name="GoldenAge" value="Golden Age"/>
	<entry name="GoldenAgeDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Through many darknesses came we. On this day at last our Lady not only gave us Her Light but passed It down unto us. Let us rejoice and humbly pray we be worthy of Her grace.&quot;<br/>    -- Lady Lilith Vermillion, Through Dusk to Dawn<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The colonists rejoice as our society reaches levels of enlightenment that would have been unthinkable back on old Earth. A nationwide celebration would probably make them very happy."/>
	<entry name="GoldenAgeProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+8 <icon texture='Resources/Morale'/> morale for 12 turns in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Growth" value="Eugenic Population Survey"/>
	<entry name="GrowthDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Men are generally more careful of the breed of their horses and dogs than of their children.&quot;<br/>    -- William Penn. Some Fruits Of Solitude, In Reflections And Maxims Relating To The Conduct Of Human Life (1693).<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Much of the limit on our population growth is down to simple, preventable failures prior to and during pregnancy. By investing a little more in a one-off survey of the most widespread genetic flaws in our population, we can improve the average genetic health of our population. This way, we can make an significant increase in the survivability of childbirth and the life-prospects of our growing population for very little effort."/>
	<entry name="GrowthProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+10% <icon texture='Resources/PositiveGrowth'/> growth in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Guerrilla" value="Guerrilla Warfare"/>
	<entry name="GuerrillaDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;The conventional army loses if it does not win. The guerrilla wins if he does not lose.&quot;<br/>    -- Henry Kissinger<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The strategy and tactics of guerrilla warfare tend to center upon the use of a small, mobile force competing against a larger, more unwieldy one. Tactics such as ambushes, sabotage, raids, the element of surprise, and extraordinary mobility are used to harass a larger and less-mobile traditional army, or strike a vulnerable target and withdraw almost immediately. We've now adapted these techniques to Pandora's unique topology."/>
	<entry name="GuerrillaProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Attributes/Power'/> power for light biological units in forests and mountains"/>
	<entry name="Harvest" value="Remote Autonomous Harvesting"/>
	<entry name="HarvestDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;If only I could make such a machine to sort the chaff from the men.&quot;<br/>    -- Prime Minister Yun Xi<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Using the standardized Tirenei drill at a fraction of its power to achieve 30 revolutions per minute allows Formers to safely extract natural minerals and nutrients from the soil with the otherwise underutilized radial suction pumps. Similar approaches that we had not thought of before can be used for Pandora's diverse terrestrial and aquatic regions to extract valuable resources from places we have not yet had a chance to populate."/>
	<entry name="HarvestProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to harvest resources from territories"/>
	<entry name="Leviathan" value="Leviathan Hide"/>
	<entry name="LeviathanDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Leviathan flesh tastes somewhat like paintstripper so requires extensive treatment for culinary use. However, its fins make an excellent broth -- but do remember to wear shielded chainmail gloves when handling it.<br/>    -- Alpheus Schreiber, The Chymical Kitchen<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The Leviathan's skin demonstrates parallel evolution to shark skin, being comprised of overlapping monomolecular tooth-like structures. This makes it both tough to break and dangerous to touch -- perfect for our waterborne units if we can replicate it."/>
	<entry name="LeviathanProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Attributes/Power'/> power for waterborne units"/>
	<entry name="Market0" value="Planetary Market"/>
	<entry name="Market0Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;The only thing sweeter than shooting an enemy with his own gun is selling it to his widow afterwards.&quot;<br/>    -- Director Eric Preston, Lethal Market Forces<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>After virtual decades of negotiation, which took mere days in real time, AI representatives of each faction have agreed to set up a planetary market. Here we can anonymously buy natural resources at prices that vary according to supply and demand. Be aware, though, that you are buying from, and selling to, your opponents."/>
	<entry name="Market0Properties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Provides access to the planetary market"/>
	<entry name="Movement" value="Advanced Time Dilation"/>
	<entry name="MovementDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;It may take us centuries to master time dilation. So we expect to be done by next Tuesday. &quot;<br/>    -- Professor Alpheus Schreiber, Stand-Up For Scientists<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Time had always been overlooked as only a matter of perception. Time compression and dilation is now a full-fledged research field and the first results are encouraging. It will probably take centuries to fully understand the manipulation of this very peculiar dimension, but it already grants us better mobility."/>
	<entry name="MovementProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+100% <icon texture='Attributes/Movement'/> movement for all units"/>	
	<entry name="Power" value="Telepathy"/>
	<entry name="PowerDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Welcome to Telepathics Anonymous. Don't bother introducing yourself.&quot;<br/>    -- Robert Barr<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The ability to read into our enemies' minds helps us predict and prevent each and every one of their movements on the battlefield. Though it doesn't mean we can win every battle, it helps."/>
	<entry name="PowerProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Attributes/Power'/> power for all units"/>
	<entry name="Pollution" value="Planetary Awareness"/>
	<entry name="PollutionDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Like splitting the atom, extinction-level events were thought the province of god alone. Yet humanity didn't also acquire god's putative morality or wisdom along with god's power, so Earth is dead. This time, we must learn.&quot;<br/>    -- Advocate Vivian Gardinier, Alien Ecosystems<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The main drawback of industrialization has always been pollution. We are not willing to repeat the mistakes we made on old Earth and monitoring of pollutant interference in the wilderness, as well as proactive actions to diminish the release of hazardous waste, can alleviate the problem."/>
	<entry name="PollutionProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>-2 <icon texture='Resources/Pollution'/> pollution in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Population" value="Advanced City Planning"/>
	<entry name="PopulationDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;We should concentrate our work not only to a separated housing problem but housing involved in our daily work and all the other functions of the city.&quot;<br/>    -- Alvar Aalto, Sketches<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Careful, rational planning and implementation of automated space management prevents population growth from being hampered by housing shortages."/>
	<entry name="PopulationProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+2 <icon texture='Resources/Habitat'/> habitat in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Production" value="Operational Efficiency"/>
	<entry name="ProductionDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;The Pyramids, Rome, The Great Wall... they weren't built by free men. You may feel like slaves today, but you're building a golden future for us all.&quot;<br/>    -- Prime Minister Yun Xi, Leadership of the State<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>In any industrialized nation, most delays and production problems stem from a single failure: that of coordination in the dispatching of human and material resources, due to petty quarrels over contractual details. Better handling of those issues by a regulating authority can help productivity."/>
	<entry name="ProductionProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Resources/Production'/> production from workers in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Research" value="Brain Growth"/>
	<entry name="ResearchDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Eierkopf. Intello. Egghead. Every language has a dismissive attitude to greater intelligence. Isn't it time that humanity ditched this beastly attitude and embraced the one thing that makes us distinct from the animals?&quot;<br/>    -- Professor Alpheus Schreiber, Stand-Up For Scientists<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Time has passed and humanity has evolved yet again. What would have looked like an abnormally swollen cranium on old Earth is now commonplace -- the average brain is now capable of a more simultaneous functions and focused tasks than ever before, and the expanded neural network gives our researchers a great advantage."/>
	<entry name="ResearchProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+25% <icon texture='Resources/Research'/> research from scientists in all cities"/>
	<entry name="Sight" value="Xenotronium Sensors"/>
	<entry name="SightDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;Unobtainium, vibranium, adamantium... I swear the scientists are just making these compounds up. But as long as they have military applications, you won't hear me complaining.&quot;<br/>    -- Admiral James Heid, On War<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Xenotronium, though rare and slightly unstable, is a chemical compound with interesting properties. Used in eyepieces, it gives properties close but immensely superior to old Earth's night vision goggles, along with heat and movement detection."/>
	<entry name="SightProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>+100% <icon texture='Attributes/Sight'/> sight for all units"/>
	<entry name="Terraform" value="Terraforming"/>
	<entry name="TerraformDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;With the best intentions, they'll make Pandora into a new Earth -- by which I mean, this planet is doomed.&quot;<br/>    -- Advocate Vivian Gardinier, The Landing Address<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Across the tundra, the city block-sized Formers spread, the ones at the front excavating, the rear contingent compressing earth and stacking rock. These improved Former fleets can flatten, raise or lower areas the size of countries in a matter of months. Given enough time, they could make this entire planet one ocean -- perhaps, save for a single unearthly mountain of carefully-stacked rock."/>
	<entry name="TerraformProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to raise terrain<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows Formers to lower terrain"/>
	<entry name="Transport" value="Naval Transportation Logistics"/>
	<entry name="TransportDescription" value="<style name='Italic'/>&quot;The ocean won't stop the Eaters. They'll build rafts and eat the fish, sharks and whales out of the sea, perhaps even the Aspidoch himself. Fish, if you're reading this; run, hide!&quot;<br/>    -- Advocate Vivian Gardinier, The Landing Address<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>A large percentage of the planetary surface is covered by water, forming an obstacle for civilian and military units alike. Naval logistics provide our empire with deployable transporters that can ship land units over the sea."/>
	<entry name="TransportProperties" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Project<br/><icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Allows land units to self-embark across water"/>
</language>
