<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language>
<!--
	The following tokens are replaced by the game in *Victory, *VictoryNear and *Defeat entries:
 
 	%1% with the year of the event, e.g. 2100.
 	%2% with the controller's faction leader title and name, e.g. "Lady Lilith Vermillion".
 	%3% with the controller's faction name, e.g. "Divine Ascension".
 	
 	The following tokens are replaced by the game in *VictoryNear and *Defeat (not EliminationDefeat) entries:
 	
 	%4% with the (near) winner's faction leader title and name, e.g. "Advocate Gardinier".
 	%5% with the (near) winner's faction name, e.g. "Terra Salvum".
-->

<!-- Flavor reports; displayed once per game. -->
	<entry name="EconomyDefeat" value="<style name='Heading'/>ECONOMIC DEFEAT!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;And, for an instant, she stared directly into those soft blue eyes and knew, with an instinctive mammalian certainty, that the exceedingly rich were no longer even remotely human.&quot;<br/>    -- William Gibson<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>It is the year %1% AD, and your empire, %3%, has become economically dependent on %5%, to the point where your colony -- soon to be taken over and forgotten -- could not survive without them.<br/><br/>There's no point even trying to rebel; before your military got to their door, they'd have bought a bigger army. If you spent another year on research, they'd transcend before you. Simply put, %5% can out-build and out-grow you at whatever you do. Surrender is the only option."/>
	<entry name="EconomyVictory" value="<style name='Heading'/>ECONOMIC VICTORY!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;The supreme art of war is to subdue the enemy without fighting.&quot;<br/>    -- Sun Tzu, The Art of War<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>You have done it, %2%. In the year %1% AD, your empire has become the single economic hub on Pandora, making you the one untouchable leader on the planet. If anyone threatens you -- you can simply buy them. Them, their guards, their home, their families... the planet, essentially, dances to the clattering of your purse.<br/><br/>A bright, liberal future awaits your empire, you and your descendants."/>
	<entry name="EliminationDefeat" value="<style name='Heading'/>ELIMINATION DEFEAT!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;What difference does it make to the dead, the orphans and the homeless, whether the mad destruction is wrought under the name of totalitarianism or in the holy name of liberty or democracy?&quot;<br/>    -- Mahatma Gandhi, Non-Violence in Peace and War<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>It is the year %1% AD, and your colony, %3%, is in ruins. Your forces are crushed, any survivors living wild on Pandora enslaved. If you make it out of your devastated fortress, you will spend the last years of your life fleeing your vengeful opponents.<br/><br/>Your ideals -- that drove you from crowded Earth to the asteroid belt, and thence to the stars -- your ideals die here. Nothing of your beliefs will survive the death of your people here."/>
	<entry name="MilitaryDefeat" value="<style name='Heading'/>MILITARY DEFEAT!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;I never thought of losing, but now that it's happened, the only thing is to do it right.&quot;<br/>    -- Muhammad Ali<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>It is the year %1% AD, and your empire, %3%, can only bow to the military power of %5% as they march upon your remaining cities. Your defeat will be bitter -- whether you surrender or die, they will be equally swift.<br/><br/>After all, great ambitions are not enough."/>
	<entry name="MilitaryVictory" value="<style name='Heading'/>MILITARY VICTORY!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Victory at all costs, victory in spite of all terror, victory however long and hard the road may be; for without victory, there is no survival.&quot;<br/>    -- Winston Churchill<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>You have done it, %2%. In the year %1% AD, your forces have crushed most resistance and whichever other factions have not been eradicated will soon surrender for fear of following suit.<br/><br/>Through the ages, you will be known as the conqueror of Pandora."/>
	<entry name="ResearchDefeat" value="<style name='Heading'/>SCIENTIFIC DEFEAT!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;I have not failed. I've just found 10,000 ways that won't work.&quot;<br/>    -- Thomas A. Edison<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>It is the year %1% AD, and your empire, %3%, can only watch in awe as %5% deploys increasingly superior technologies. As their structures reach to Pandora's burning heavens, you realise that all resistance is useless -- your only hope is to plead for a part in their transcendance.<br/><br/>Sometimes humility is the best plan."/>
	<entry name="ResearchVictory" value="<style name='Heading'/>SCIENTIFIC VICTORY!<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Man cannot discover new oceans unless he has the courage to lose sight of the shore.&quot;<br/>    -- André Gide, The Counterfeiters<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>You have done it, %2%. In the year %1% AD, your state of enlightenment has left all adversaries trailing behind. Your engines of science burn brighter and faster than any of your competitors -- and your minds see deeper in the universe's fundamentals than any others.<br/><br/>Your empire will be the motor and flagbearer of innovation and civilization for many generations to come."/>

	<entry name="AlienAggressionImminent" value="<style name='Heading'/>Xenomorph Activities<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Maybe this world is another planet's hell.&quot;<br/>    -- Aldous Huxley<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>We are receiving troublesome reports from the frontiers that large swarms of Xenomorphs are gathering and roaming the lands. The number of incidents due to conflicts with alien lifeforms is on the rise; several civilian explorers have gone missing over the last months.<br/><br/>Is the planet already reacting to our intrusion? Whatever may be the cause, we should garrison our cities to prepare for the worst."/>
	<entry name="AlienGenocideComplete" value="<style name='Heading'/>Alien Genocide Complete<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Extinction is the rule. Survival is the exception.&quot;<br/>    -- Carl Sagan<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>On Earth, we hadn't managed to eliminate native life, despite our best efforts; foxes, rats, and pigeons survived where we'd wiped out everything else.<br/><br/>Here, life didn't have time to adapt. In the trees, nothing moves. The oceans are empty, save for the roughest phytoplankton. In the air, only escaped Earth insects flutter uncertainly, rapidly adapting to the alien food and gravity. On the plains, where the ur-bison once roamed, now mouldering piles of bones are testment to the efficacy of our weapons. Save for laboratories, zoos and rare semi-domesticated xenos, native life on this planet is extinct.<br/><br/>I think this experiment has confirmed the long-held hypothesis; men really are the monsters."/>
	<entry name="AlienSighted" value="<style name='Heading'/>Alien Sighted<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;I'm sure the universe is full of intelligent life. It's just been too intelligent to come here.&quot;<br/>    -- Arthur C. Clarke<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Life! This planet is fertile indeed. From the scuttling sheets of tiny myelinated bugs that rove the land to the batwinged flocks (eerily reminiscent of Earth's prehistoric Pteranodons) to the leviathans of the seas -- life is everywhere!<br/><br/>We should proceed cautiously. Though they don't appear to be aggressive -- indeed, they're mostly vegetarian, bizarre for an ecosystem on this scale -- we have no clue as to what might trigger hostility."/>
	<entry name="AllianceForged" value="<style name='Heading'/>Alliance Forged<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;There are no words to express the abyss between isolation and having one ally. It may be conceded to the mathematician that four is twice two. But two is not twice one; two is two thousand times one.&quot;<br/>    -- G.K. Chesterton, The Man Who Was Thursday<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The negotiations to start negotiations took six months and were first conducted only by remote drones in the wasteland. Eventually, we agreed a location for the talks, and sent bodyguards, spies, food-tasters, shielding-trucks, poison-sniffers, translators, entertainers, gifts and finally our ambassadors. And we talked.<br/><br/>Now, we have allies. Allies to share the horrors of this world with, to share the struggle against our enemies with, to share suspicion, jealousy and resentment with. To share our trust with? That will take a lot, lot longer. But this is a start."/>
	<entry name="CityBuilt" value="<style name='Heading'/>Colony Established<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;This City is what it is because our citizens are what they are.&quot;<br/>    -- Plato<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>This is a great day for mankind. Today, we've established our first habitation on a foreign world. The scientific and mechanical marvels it took to bring us to this point should not be belittled -- but it's better to look to the future rather than the past.<br/><br/>At the moment, our colony might only be a few thousand souls, but given time and peace, we hope that it swell to rival the cities of Earth - except that here, we have clean water, clean soil and room to grow.<br/><br/>It's humanity's only chance for a fresh start. Let's hope that we can take it."/>
	<entry name="CityRazedByAliens" value="<style name='Heading'/>City Razed By Aliens<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;People speak sometimes about the 'bestial' cruelty of man, but that is terribly unjust and offensive to beasts, no animal could ever be so cruel as a man, so artfully, so artistically cruel.&quot;<br/>    -- Fyodor Dostoyevsky, The Brothers Karamazov<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Once past the walls, the aliens spread out. Each one behaved like the proverbial fox in a chicken shed. Men, women, children were torn down where they stood, slept, wept and hid. Those they didn't eat, the aliens shredded in a frenzy. And those who fled into the shelter of the fungus fields never came out.<br/><br/>Once all the people were dead, the planet started on the buildings, already rent and burnt in the battle. Acid from the attack seeped into the more secure foundations, roots and giant rotifiers tore up the less-fixed structures, and the endlessly-invasive fungi dissolved the prefab walls.<br/><br/>Within a few weeks, there was no trace of man."/>
	<entry name="CityUnrest" value="<style name='Heading'/>City Unrest<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Wars will be stopped only when soldiers refuse to fight, when workers refuse to load weapons onto ships and aircraft, when people boycott the economic outposts of Empire that are strung across the globe.&quot;<br/>    -- Arundhati Roy, Public Power in the Age of Empire<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The harvests rot in the fields as the labourers doze on the hay. The dull rumble of the mining machines beneath our feet is inconsistent and occasionally falls silent. The factorymen sleep on the job, and their overseers say nothing. Everything takes more time than it should. Clearly, the people are unhappy.<br/><br/>Only the military shoulder their weapons; they grumble, but they still defend the colony. If we want to recover from this slump, we need to focus on satisfying their complaints."/>
	<entry name="EliminatedFaction" value="<style name='Heading'/>Eliminated Faction<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;In individuals, insanity is rare; but in groups, parties, nations and epochs, it is the rule.&quot;<br/>    -- Friedrich Nietzsche, Beyond Good and Evil<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>One of our fellow colonies has failed, wiped out by gun, tooth or simple starvation. Of course, their beliefs don't die with them -- we're not as monolithic as that. As amongst vegetarians there are vegans and fish-eaters, so among our surviving factions, there is a remnant of them.<br/><br/>But their particular form of madness -- their decision that there was just one way that humans should live -- that's gone, probably forever. And we can't say that we're sorry."/>
	<entry name="EmpirePollutionThresholdReached" value="<style name='Heading'/>The Air Can't Get Any Dirtier<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;There's so much pollution in the air now that if it weren't for our lungs there'd be no place to put it all.&quot;<br/>    -- Robert Orben<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Amazing! We've managed to actually beat our record for pollution back at home. The colonies are covered in smog, the streets are knee-deep in junk and sewage, and the native species are dying off spectacularly quickly. We really know how to make this place feel like home."/>
	<entry name="EnemyCityCaptured" value="<style name='Heading'/>Enemy City Captured<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;It has been claimed at times that our modern age of technology facilitates dictatorship. What we must understand is that the industries, processes, and inventions created by modern science can be used either to subjugate or liberate. The choice is up to us.&quot;<br/>    -- Henry A. Wallace<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>As our troops enter the colony, the babble ceases. Sullen faces line the streets, bruised and dirty from the fighting. The only accompaniment to the rhythmic tread of our troopers' boots are the cries of the injured and dying elsewhere in the city. One day, these dismal, conquered humans could be our families, from our city.<br/><br/>This city is ours, for now. And we can never rest until we've removed every threat from the planet -- including other humans."/>
	<entry name="WeEnteredEra1" value="<style name='Heading'/>Mechanization Era<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;The factory of the future will have only two employees, a man and a dog. The man will be there to feed the dog. The dog will be there to keep the man from touching the equipment.&quot;<br/>    -- Warren G. Bennis<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Our factories run endlessly, perfectly. Each worker oversees an army of machines by himself from the security of his home. Each researcher works with carefully-crippled AIs to probe the secrets of the planet. Man's role in the universe is now solely in planning and direction.<br/><br/>Machines have allowed us to leave our cradle and reach solar systems many light years away at the edge of our galaxy. With Pandora we have finally discovered a planet filled with life, and albeit alien and dangerous, our machines will once again pave the way to human supremacy. Or will they? The relics of alien technology indicate that the former inhabitants were fairly advanced, yet they are gone without a trace -- and their creations are crumbling into dust..."/>
	<entry name="WeEnteredEra2" value="<style name='Heading'/>Transcendence Era<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;There are only two forces in the world, the sword and the spirit. In the long run the sword will always be conquered by the spirit.&quot;<br/>    -- Napoleon Bonaparte<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Imagine a world beyond materialism, where each and every individual of our society can enjoy a peaceful life in wealth and safety. Where we no longer have to fight for limited resources or suffer nature's wrath. An ideal world absent of any fear for survival but filled with joy and delight.<br/><br/>After millenia of progress, the technologies to let this dream become reality are finally within our reach."/>
	<entry name="HiveCleared" value="<style name='Heading'/>Hive Cleared<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;I discovered that if one looks a little closer at this beautiful world, there are always red ants underneath.&quot;<br/>    -- David Lynch<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Storming the hive was hard and bloody, but eventually the last of the xenomorphs fell. At its heart, we found a queen, surrounded by an acre of eggs, all ripe to hatch and spill death on our colony. We burned the hive, we burned her, we burned them.<br/><br/>We did not hate them -- to hate a simple beast bent on survival is futile -- but it was us or them. And who would you choose?"/>
	<entry name="LostCityControl" value="<style name='Heading'/>Lost City Control<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Just because you can read, write and do a little math, doesn't mean that you're entitled to conquer the universe.&quot;<br/>    -- Kurt Vonnegut, Hocus Pocus<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Where we slept, last night, now someone else sleeps. Our families are now someone else's, kowtowing to their disastrous beliefs. We console ourselves that they live, but they are no longer ours.<br/><br/>There is a strangeness in this. The military defeat -- the loss of so many of our troops, so easily and brutally -- hurts, but not as much as knowing that someone else has our people under their boot. Can our pride withstand this humiliation? How shall we reclaim our homes, our families?"/>
	<entry name="ObservatoryExplored" value="<style name='Heading'/>Alien Observation Tower Explored<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;The more clearly we can focus our attention on the wonders and realities of the universe about us, the less taste we shall have for the destruction of our race. Wonder and humility are wholesome emotions, and they do not exist side by side with a lust for destruction.&quot;<br/>    -- Rachel Carson<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>When the first explorer hove into view of these impossible towers, we assumed they were a form of gigantic local fauna -- a scaled-up thistle, perhaps, that drew its life from pressure differentials between the atmospheric layers. Approaching closer, we took them to be astronomical observatories -- why else would one build something so sky-scraping?<br/><br/>They are observatories, yes, but not as we assumed. From inside, the facets of the crystalline domes provide a perfect view of the surrounding countryside and obscure, antique devices inside allow us to peer within the crust of the planet itself, or to track the skittering beasts on its surface. Properly utilised, this will provide a great leap forward for our research."/>
	<entry name="PopulationLimitReached" value="<style name='Heading'/>Severe Overcrowding<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;The slum is the measure of civilization.&quot;<br/>    -- Jacob Riis<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Our cities burst with life. In our colony's cramped and sweaty streets, men are born and die, never venturing into the alien world. Others do anything to get out, working the dangerous formers beyond the city's limits to terraform the land, or exploring the planet's limits in the army. Yet, still there isn't enough room for all to do everything, and the people are not happy.<br/><br/>What I'm saying, is -- we need more space. Fast."/>
	<entry name="PlanetFullyExplored" value="<style name='Heading'/>Planet Fully Explored<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;We shall not cease from exploration, and the end of all our exploring will be to arrive where we started and know the place for the first time.&quot;<br/>    -- T. S. Eliot, Little Gidding<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Pandora is a Super-Earth. This means it has 3.24 times the surface area of Earth, and we've explored nearly everything. There's not a single sector of this planet that our outriders haven't visited. Of course, we've not covered every inch -- we've not dived into volcanoes or plumbed the sea's depths -- but we've seen every last bit."/>
	<entry name="ExploringTheRuin" value="<style name='Heading'/>Exploring The Ruin<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;We could imagine nothing pleasanter than to spend all of our lives digging for relics of the past.&quot;<br/>    -- Heinrich Schliemann<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>We knew these ruins weren't built by human hand -- but now we're more worried about what destroyed them. These structures are far beyond our capabilities, able to withstand all we could throw at them -- even our diamond drills can't remove the polish from their surface.<br/><br/>Yet here they lie, hollow ruins, the inhabitants long ago scooped out. And they definitely weren't built by the local species we've encountered so far. Thankfully, they were destroyed millennia ago so, hopefully, their destroyers are long gone too."/>
	<entry name="RuinInSight" value="<style name='Heading'/>Ruin In Sight<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Where there is ruin, there is hope for a treasure.&quot;<br/>    -- Rumi<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>After the debacle of the Martian canals, generations of astronomers learned to restrain their hopes. After all, the scientists always said that the chances of finding intelligent life within a thousand light years were infinitesimally small. So when we saw these structures from space, as the drop ships powered up, we thought our imaginations were running away with us again.<br/><br/>Now, looking on them with our own eyes for the first time, we can see that they are artificial -- and not, just off-the-shelf beauty, but spectacular, elegant structures, built out of cobwebs and light, but stronger than diamond. Perhaps their creators are still here too? The sweetest dream of mankind is to encounter intelligent life and find it friendly -- imagine what we could share!"/>
	<entry name="SpecialAlienKilled" value="<style name='Heading'/>The Great Hunt<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;It is not the strongest of the species that survives, nor the most intelligent that survives. It is the one that is the most adaptable to change.&quot;<br/>    -- Charles Darwin<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>The surviving soldiers told me that, when the killer round was fired into the great beast's last heart, it stumbled and for a moment looked as if it was thinking about something profound. Its head sagged back into its ragged neck, and shuddered like it was about to laugh. Then, with the sound of a tower block falling asleep, it died.<br/><br/>On Earth, we hunted the great creatures of the sea relentlessly, for food, oil and perfume, until we'd nearly wiped them out. All very sad, of course, but it's part of making the planet fit for man. And who knows what we'll be able to harvest from this corpse?"/>
	<entry name="WarDeclared" value="<style name='Heading'/>War Has Been Declared<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;I launched the phrase 'the war to end war' and that was not the least of my crimes.&quot;<br/>    -- H.G. Wells<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>War has come to Pandora. Though the history books will neaten up its origin, here, in the mess of a freshly colonised world, the reasons aren't clear why it started. Whether it was a slow accretion of grudges on one side, philosophical differences on another, or the plain horror of human bloodlust after our battles with the aliens, we can't see from our position in history. But war is here."/>
	<entry name="WeBuiltBlackHoleGenerator" value="<style name='Heading'/>Black Hole Generator Complete<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;There are risks which are not acceptable: the destruction of humanity is one of them.&quot;<br/>    -- Friedrich Durrenmatt<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>What... what have we made? Nuclear weaponry, we understand, was deadly. But in our hands we have the power to tear stars asunder, carefully constrained by technology. That our research has come this far without destroying this solar system was more through luck than knowledge... we will never know how close we were.<br/><br/>Now we have a weapon which, whilst not quite a true black hole, draws something similar into place for the smallest fraction of a minute. Time enough for its maw to snap out across a country and draw all that lived or existed there into an eternity of consumption on the lip of the event horizon. I shudder that we may one day use this."/>
	<entry name="WeBuiltNuclearLaunchCenter" value="<style name='Heading'/>Nuclear Launch Center Complete<style name='Italic'/><br/><br/>&quot;Of all the failed technologies that litter the onward march of science -- steam carriages, zeppelins, armoured trains -- none has been so catastrophic to prosperity as the last century's attempt to generate electricity from nuclear fission.&quot;<br/>    -- James Buchan<style name='Default'/><br/><br/>Nuclear weapons. We fired them only twice in anger back on Earth -- and even in our moments of desperation, never since. Let's hope they work equally well as a deterrent, both to our enemies and to ourselves, up here."/>
	<entry name="Welcome" value="Welcome to Pandora,<br/>%1%!"/>
	<!-- 1/3 progress to invasion <entry name="Invasion0" value="Ruins of an old civilization can be found throughout the surface. Who were they? What happened to them?"/> -->
	<!-- 2/3 progress to invasion <entry name="Invasion1" value="The alien ruins seem to be emitting some sort of signal."/> -->
	<!-- 3/3 progress to invasion <entry name="Invasion2" value="They came from the skies. An invasion without warning."/> -->
	<!-- 1/3 invasion cleared <entry name="Invasion3" value="They call themselves The Skorg. Beings fused with machinery. Their technology is far superior to ours. All our communication attempts have been ignored and they continue attacking us at all fronts. We must unite as a species if we are to drive them back and preserve humanity."/> -->
	<!-- 2/3 invasion cleared <entry name="Invasion4" value="We have retrieved some information from a captured Skorg. All data suggests that they view us as a petty species. They have been roaming from world to world only to strip them of all resources and move on. At this rate, Pandora will be ruined even if we are victorious."/> -->
	<!-- 3/3 invasion cleared <entry name="Invasion5" value="Finally, the Skorg invasion appears to have stopped. We have shown them that Humans are not to be underestimated. Pandora, however, is in a state of decay and we must be wary to not repeat Earth's history."/> -->
	
<!-- News reports. -->
	<entry name="BlackHoleGeneratorBuilt" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : %5% Finish Construction Of A Black Hole Generator<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Our science correspondent Professor Meat E. O'er has reported that he's detected a substantial increase in the mass of Pandora, which can only be explained by the invention of a black hole generator. Hopefully, the inventors intend to use it just for peaceful purposes -- though we're not quite sure what those could be, except for a really efficient trash can.<br/><br/>And the weather: if it's used, we'll be slowly stretched across the event horizon of this black hole for all eternity. So wear a cagoule.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="EconomyVictoryNear" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : %5% Emerges As Economic Superpower<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Reports are coming in that %4% has more money than god. Word on the street is that soon %4% will be able to buy every last unit on the planet.<br/><br/>If the others want to stand a chance of dominating Pandora, they either need to start saving up or go full-out military on %4%'s ass. Not that little old me should be advising you on tactics.<br/><br/>And the weather: showers of gold and precious jewels are predicted over the areas owned by %4%. If you want to avoid being cut to ribbons, remember to take your molybdenum brollies with you at all times!&quot;"/>
	<entry name="FactionEliminated" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : %5% Eliminated<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>We're hearing reports that the %5% faction has been wiped off the face of Pandora. We have no details on this breaking news.<br/><br/>And the weather: the sky is crying. Wait, that's rain.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="GlobalPollutionThresholdReached" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : This Planet Can't Get Any More Polluted<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Global pollution has *cough, cough.* has reached a saturation point *cough, cough*. Okay, can we stop filling the atmosphere with crap please? *cough* I can't breathe.<br/><br/>And the weather: a lethal smog has spread over two thirds of the planet's surface, so always carry a spare oxygen tank.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="MilitaryVictoryNear" value="<style name='Heading'/>%5% Approach Military Domination<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Our military analysts have been looking at %4%'s current military strength and we think it's mighty fine! We'd think you'd have to be mad to go up against them.<br/><br/>If the others want to stand a chance of dominating Pandora, they either need to focus on growth or go help their allies whale on %4%'s ass. Not that little old me should be advising you on tactics.<br/><br/>And the weather: there will be brief lead, laser and atomic storms in areas resisting %4%. Our advice; take your rads pills twice daily and use Factor 5000 sunscreen inside your bunker.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="NuclearLaunchCenterBuilt" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : %5% Complete A Nuclear Launch Center<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Our science correspondent Professor Meat E. O'er has reported that his geiger counters are picking up a whole bunch of overcharged gamma rays, which means someone has managed to rebuild some h-bombs and test them underground. Well done you! Now... please don't bomb us.<br/><br/>And the weather: lots of charged particles in the atmosphere tonight. Wear lead pants and try to avoid getting atomised out there, folks!&quot;"/>
	<entry name="ResearchVictoryNear" value="<style name='Heading'/>Breaking : %5% Achieve Scientific Breakthroughs Galore<style name='Default'/><br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>&quot;This is Missy McDee from the Pandora Wire Service, bringing you the latest news and weather, 400 hours a day, 28 days a year.<br/><br/>Now, I don't rightly know what those brainboxes over at %4% think they're up to, but they're way ahead of the rest of us.<br/><br/>If the others want to stand a chance of dominating Pandora, they either need to focus on research themselves or just build some good old fashioned-WMD. Not that little old me should be advising you on tactics.<br/><br/>And the weather: around the %4% base, the weather has taken become quantumly entangled, so, locals,  make sure you wear your snowshoes *and* your sunglasses, as you transcend to a higher plane of existence.&quot;"/>

<!-- Reward reports. -->
	<entry name="CreditsReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Resources/Credits'/> credits"/>
	<entry name="FoodReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Resources/Food'/> food"/>
	<entry name="MineralsReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Resources/Minerals'/> minerals"/>
	<entry name="PolluteReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Wasteland has spread around the ruin"/>
	<entry name="ResearchReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Resources/Research'/> research"/>
	<entry name="HiveDestroyed" value="Hive Destroyed"/>
	<entry name="HiveDestroyedCreditsReward" value="Your troops have successfully wiped out a Xenomorph colony that served as a hatchery for roaming Xenomorphs.<br/><br/>Nearby cities can feel safer now, and the hive was harbouring a significant amount of valuable raw materials as well as trophies that can be sold on the planetary market."/>
	<entry name="RuinExplored" value="Ruin Explored"/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredCreditsReward" value="Scavenging through an old ruin left behind by a race long forgotten, your troops discover some items of value."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredFoodReward" value="Scavenging through an old ruin left behind by a race long forgotten, your field scientists discover remnants of an alien plant growth fertilizer."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredMineralsReward" value="Scavenging through an old ruin left behind by a race long forgotten, your troops discover a large chunk of minerals in a derelict storage facility."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredPolluteReward" value="While exploring an ancient ruin, your troops accidently release an alien contaminant that is deadly for the planet's flora and fauna."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredResearchReward" value="After analyzing mysterious inscriptions on the surfaces of an ancient ruin, your scientists are able to incorporate it into their work."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredTechnologyReward" value="While looking through an ancient ruin, your troops come upon a piece of unknown technology which your scientist are able to use."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredUnitReward" value="While exploring an ancient ruin, your troops stumble upon a doglike pack of xenomorph drones which have been separated from their collective mind, and are now strangely domesticated."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredUnitDamageReward" value="While exploring an ancient ruin, your troops accidently trigger an explosive trap most likely put in place to protect against alien wildlife."/>
	<entry name="RuinExploredUnitRankReward" value="While exploring an ancient ruin, your troops show outstanding tactical fortitude by dispatching a lair of man-sized alien leeches without suffering any casualties."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExplored" value="Sunken Ruin Explored"/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredCreditsReward" value="Scavenging through a sunken ruin constructed by a race long forgotten, your troops discover some items of value."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredFoodReward" value="Scavenging through a sunken ruin constructed by a race long forgotten, your field scientists discover remnants of nutrient-rich seaweed."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredMineralsReward" value="Scavenging through a sunken ruin constructed by a race long forgotten, your troops discover a large chunk of minerals in a drowned storage facility."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredResearchReward" value="After analyzing mysterious inscriptions on the surfaces of an ancient sunken ruin, your scientists are able to incorporate it into their work."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredTechnologyReward" value="While looking through a sunken ruin, your troops come upon a piece of unknown technology which your scientist are able to use."/>
	<entry name="SunkenRuinExploredUnitRankReward" value="While exploring a sunken ruin, your troops show outstanding tactical fortitude by dispatching a lair of man-sized alien leeches without suffering any casualties."/>
	<entry name="TechnologyReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Discovered %1%"/>
	<entry name="UnitReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Units/BugIcon' height='16'/> Xenomorph Drones"/>
	<entry name="UnitDamageReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Suffered <style color='Red'/>%2$.2f<style color='Default'/> unit damage"/>
	<entry name="UnitRankReward" value="<icon texture='GUI/Bullet'/>Gained %2$.0f <icon texture='Attributes/Rank'/> unit ranks"/>
</language>
