<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language>
	<entry name="0Description" value="(Personalised edition, Dave Rimster, Grade 93, Church of the Baptismal Ordnance.)<br/><br/>Dear Dave,<br/><br/>This is my personal gospel. As I'm sure you're becoming aware, whatever branch of faith someone adheres to, the message of Divine Revelation is true for them. We are all unenlightened sinners (as evinced by your SpaceNook pages that I'm glancing through right now -- I'm amazed you got away with that blackmail attempt when you were 17), but neither redemption nor enlightenment are beyond us. Indeed, I too was once a wastrel, as sinful and ignorant as you. Let me tell you a story.<br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>The saloon doors bash open as I fly through them, then again as a cheap Shieldlite suitcase follows me, spilling the paraphernalia of addiction across the street. &quot;And stay out!&quot; comes the traditional yell. With an air of practised resignation, I, Lily Maroon, pick up my case, pack it, flip open my phone, dial a number, and start walking. &quot;Hi Joe, it's Lil...&quot; The phone cuts off, audibly. I whistle, amused, and try again.<br/><br/>Many streets and many calls later, it's getting dark when a phone call is finally answered amenably.<br/><br/>&quot;Come on in, Lily.&quot; Franklin's house is sparse and serious, with movie posters on the walls and computer hardware taking up what once was the sitting room. &quot;You'll be sleeping upstairs, in the utility room.&quot; I make a move for the stairs, but Franklin stops me. He's a sparsely-built man himself, close-shouldered but he's always put up with my visits -- except now he's being serious. &quot;Lil, I have to say, there are a few house rules. No drugs, social, legal or pharmaceutical. No whoring. No scams. No stealing or lawbreaking in general.&quot; This sounds like no fun at all! I openmy mouth to protest but he shushes me. &quot;And you'll be working for me until you find something better. It's a social media start-up called SpaceNook. You used to be a damn good programmer -- and I need that. I can pay well&quot;. In the dark, I smile. &quot;Sure, Franklin. Sounds like a plan.&quot; That was the start.<br/><br/><style name='Default'/>Of course, as soon as the chance came for real power -- real money -- I seized it. SpaceNook, under my guidance, rapidly achieved a global scale, absorbing the lesser social networks, and Franklin eventually was persuaded to step aside, letting me become CEO. But power didn't make me a better person. It's important to remember that the gods are always watching.<br/><br/>On the side, I'd started up another business, a religious network tied into SpaceNook, called Divine Ascension. It was just a simple application of economic principles to the religious market. I made a religion for everyone, every variant of diseased mind and devotion, all built using off-the-shelf AIs and SpaceNook's white-labelled back-end.<br/><br/>It's amazing how fervent worshippers become when they realise you've got access to all their dirty secrets, isn't it, Dave? And what did you do with that Vietnam-era grenade, anyway?<br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>At some point I was Mrs Maroon, CEO of SpaceNook and Divine Ascension. I know, big leap. I sat in my glass-walled office on the 90th floor of some architect's penile fantasy, idly going through a fellow CEO's SpaceNook page, trawling for dirt, when I heard shouting. Through the glazed double doors of my office, I saw a familiar thin figure arguing with my secretary, Butch, unaware of the security apes coming up behind him. I buzzed through. &quot;Let him in, Butch.&quot; I say. &quot;And tell security to stand down. For now.&quot;<br/><br/>Franklin walks through the doors, flustered. &quot;Franklin, my dear,&quot; I start, before he cut me off. He was always doing that.&quot;Lilith, we have to talk. I know what you've been up to with the user data. It can't carry on. You'll get arrested.&quot;<br/><br/>I turned away, mainly to hide my smile. &quot;Oh, Franklin, don't be so naive. We're protected. I've a top-notch team whose job it is just to manage the senators, prime ministers, bishops, judges and so on. If we ever had government trouble, they would too. Anyway, all I'm asking for is donations to these very worthy religious causes. That's no crime, is it?&quot;<br/><br/>Franklin snorted. &quot;Does any of that money go to anyone but you, I wonder? What have you done to-&quot;<br/><br/>There was a strange clicking noise from the floor-to-ceiling window and a hole appeared in my desk. And another. Standing quickly, I saw the glass crazing like the world's fastest spiderweb. I never felt the bullet hit me.<br/><br/><style name='Default'/>Of course, I'd posited, unwisely perhaps, that my competitors were rational actors -- but not how rational. I'd assumed that they'd take one look at the horrible dirt I had on them and the minute demands I was making and just play along. However, one of them, and even with all the world's dirty secrets at my fingertips I never found out who, had taken out a very valuable contract on my life. The only bullet that hit me went through my frontal cortex.<br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>I floated on clouds, an angelic vision of a new world built in god's image in front of me. Through the haze I heard broken phrases; &quot;...massive stroke... ...age to prefrontal cortex... huge personality shift likely if... opiates to keep her under...&quot; and Franklin's face swam in and out of my view as he sits at my bedside. But I didn't want to wake up. This new world was so tantalizing, so real, that it mattered more. While I slept, everything changed.<br/><br/><style name='Default'/>It wasn't just the near-death experience, or the missing pound of grey matter, but I woke with a whole new outlook on life. I knew that all the nastiness we'd made -- all the blackmail I'd done -- had been with a true motive in mind, even if I hadn't realised it at the time, hadn't known it was part of God's plan. I'd built the perfect society for bringing people closer to God, a God I too now believed in. And I had a mission now.<br/><br/>I redesigned Divine Ascension. Instead of being a million separate churches, now it was truly one. I set it up like a game, so that as you progressed through the levels of the church's knowledge you give up more of your secrets, property and freedom, in return for more of the church's secrets -- and a top-grade secret of all of them is that they're all part of Divine Ascension. Churches of Christians, Muslims, Scientologists, Samaritans, Sikhs, Nuwaubians and the rest. Churches for the truly moral, for the greedy, for the racially-pure, or even for gun-nuts like you. All one.<br/><br/>The big plan, which you're going to help me with Dave, is to go to Pandora, the new planet. Pandora is our promised land -- our new home, our homage to God, the end of all our pilgrimagesand hajjes. We are going to take this world and remake it in God's image.<br/><br/>And Dave, you have been chosen to help. Of course, it's not mandatory. But you've told my church *so* many interesting stories in confession. I particularly like that one about the endangered sea eagles and the high-powered rifle. So, if you don't fancy doing God's work on an alien world, you could stay here and help the police with their enquiries instead. I'm sure they'll be dying to talk to you.<br/><br/>Anyway, I'm guessing I'll see you on Pandora! God's love and blessings,<br/><br/>Lilith Vermillion, Founder, Divine Ascension."/>
	<entry name="0Name" value="The Gospel of Lilith Vermillion"/>
	<entry name="1Description" value="<style name='Italic'/>The itch... had returned. After an age of peace, She had woken from uneasy dreaming to find a scrabbling against Her flanks, a handful of crawling contacts worrying at Her. Her memory strained to remember the sensation, uniquely ominous in Her experience. Whilst she sifted millennia of her history, long-dormant membranes on the scale of fields read out and overwrote, the sensations spread, deepened...<br/><br/><style name='Default'/>Striding between bastioned structures, Procurator-General Suleimann brandished his antique clipboard as a symbol of authority. He ducked into the corpsmen's bunkers and noted the scuffing on their boots. On the production lines, the sweating workers doubled their efforts as he passed. Ears dulled in protective headgear, deep underground, he watched mining robots blasting the rare ores from the surrounding Earth and, nodding, he made his inevitable notes. Atop a spindly windmill, a hundred metres up where the researchers risked their lives to dredge the air for ideas, he gazed down on the whole of the colony, from the tight-packed down-tents to the bureaucratic centre, to the remains of the landing craft and then outward to the reinforced plascrete walls, manned with sentries. He nearly smiled.<br/><br/>Ducking into the command bunker he nodded past two guards. Behind a functional desk sat Admiral Heid, burly with authority, toying with his rosary. A corpsman stood behind his shoulder. &quot;Report.&quot; Heid barked.<br/><br/>&quot;All is nominal, according to predictions.&quot; reported Suleimann, stiff-faced. &quot;All units are performing admirably, production and research are on track, and casualties are within expected bounds. Monkhouse lost a man to an unfocused mining laser and a soldier died from drinking methanol in illicit moonshine. We've already found the still and-&quot;<br/><br/>The Admiral glanced up at Suleimann. &quot;You're not telling me about the natives. Are they reacting?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Ah. We've encountered no hostility from the wildlife, though we've avoided approaching too closely. Ecologist Oniha recommends we try to stay distinct from any part of the ecosystem -- prey or predator -- and ensure that we take no direct action against the apex lifeforms for the moment.&quot;<br/><br/>The admiral leaned back. &quot;Oniha is an idealist.&quot; he said &quot;Until the researchers have a better idea about what we're dealing with, it's not wise to relax. Do the corpsmen know about her opinions?&quot; Suleimann nodded, uncomfortable.<br/><br/>&quot;That was unwise, but the damage is done. Sergeant, ensure all watches are doubled, as are the penalties for dereliction of duty. One hole in our defences could cost us everything. Dismissed.&quot; The corpsman nodded and hurried out. Suleimann bowed and turned to follow.<br/><br/>&quot;Suleimann -- George -- while I'm stuck behind my desk, you're my eyes out there. Don't let me down.&quot;<br/><br/><style name='Italic'/>The threat was again apparent, the archives had been found and She finally remembered what She needed to do. Mentally She shrugged. In her abdomen, a hundred eggs blossomed new, vicious life from a dozen species. And, scattered across the planet, that inoculating life closed on the causes of Her woes...<br/><br/><style name='Default'/>The terrible gale abated, the windmill's mad oscillation slowed and ceased. Suleimann wiped the sweat from his eyes and dragged himself up to peer over the flimsy guardrail. A scene of disaster met his eyes. The compound's high wall was a gap- toothed wreck where xenos had thrown their lives against it, wave after wave. Medical technicians were dragging aside the wailing, sobbing injured. Dark, acrid smoke rose from where the few able bodied corpsmen were incinerating corpses both human and alien, while reinforcements hurried to shore up the walls.<br/><br/>The sole researcher who'd stayed with him in the windmill's nest moved carefully, warily over along the platform to Suleimann. &quot;Sir? We barely survived that. Will we get support from the other colonies?&quot;<br/><br/>Suleimann shook his head, mute. The researcher looked grim. &quot;Sir, with respect. If that's what I think it is, we'll need it.&quot; The researcher pointed to the hills and proffered her binocs. Looking through them, Suleimann saw one of the great xeno structures that had seemed so dead when they arrived. Its surface roiled like a wet balloon and split, birthing a new squad of the insectile monsters. &quot;Mother of...&quot; he muttered, and ran for the stairs, leaving his clipboard spinning in his wake..."/>
	<entry name="1Name" value="The Hive"/>
	<entry name="2Description" value="<style name='Heading'/>Imperium Headquarters, Ceres, Asteroid Belt.<br/><style name='Default'/>Admiral James Heid, nominal head of the Solar System's premiere mercenary organisation, Imperium, was not a man prone to anger. Yet, his hands gripped his interrupted reading material a little harder as his adjutant, Suleimann, read out his findings.<br/><br/>&quot;...and following the discovery of the extrasolar planets, the three core factions -- Togra, Solar and Noxium -- have been quietly collaborating on building up colony ships to go to these worlds. It's unique non-replicable tech. And we're, uh, not invited to the party.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Damn. Noxium has been our ally for fifty years. Why screw us now?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;With respect, sir, James. They're just playing the Great Game. Fifty years of affection means nothing. To be betrayed in this way... Well, I see it as flattery. It means they see us as a real threat. And they know they can't move against us, nor us against them. We should leave Pandora to them. It means nothing to us.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;I disagree. We need to be on this planet -- who knows what military tech they'll find out there? We can't have them coming back here and taking us down. No, we need one of their ships. But you're right that we can't attack. If only I can think of a way of getting that ship.&quot; He looked down at the copy of the Odyssey in his hands and frowned.<br/><br/><style name='Heading'/>Callisto Station, the Asteroid Belt.<br/><style name='Default'/>Security captain Darin stared out the porthole on Callisto's security station. There, floating immense in the stardock, was the Player of Games, Noxium's prototype interstellar colony ship. His job was to defend that, against whatever enemies might be out there. His gaze drifted to the turrets surrounding it, his office and the entire stardock complex. With a near- infinite range, the turrets made his job too easy.<br/><br/>Still, he was obviously concerned as he bent over his control panel. The shipping arcs on Callisto station's traffic control screen were mostly nominal, save for a cluster of mining transports coming in from the asteroid belt. He could see that four of the steel shippers were all gradually drifting off route.<br/><br/>He tutted to himself and called through on the radio. &quot;Transporters #3358, #3367, #3248, and #2800. You seem to be drifting off course. Can you explain? You need to correct.&quot;<br/><br/>The lead trucker radioed back. &quot;#2800 here, chief. Yeah, we seem to have extra mass, funny. We're all newer models, save mine, so it's not a systems error. Could be dust accretion from our stop at Ceres, I guess?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;We're on max security, #2800. I'm going to have to inspect. Out.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Five-by-five. We'll correct trajectory in the meantime. Out.&quot;<br/><br/>Darin shut down the connection and headed out, gathering his security teams as he went.<br/><br/><style name='Heading'/>Noxium Headquarters, New New York, Earth.<br/><style name='Default'/>The boardroom of the Noxium corporation fitted every stereotype you might expect, as did the men sat around the long, oval table. Thin men, fat men, old men, slick young men -- but all men. Handmade suits that cost more than a house, immeasurably valuable paintings on the walls, discreet and smart adornments. The descendants of men who'd inherited, bought, and stolen power, the Noxium board knew how valuable morality was, down to the fraction of a cent.<br/><br/>The chairmanship and CEO, Eric Preston, was the young scion of an ancient mercantile family, as old as the Fuggers but more subtle. Despite his youth, Preston commanded respect around the board. When other children had been playing with dolls and soldiers, he'd been playing the markets, literally, gambling his pocket money to build up a hedge fund that had made him independently wealthy before he even came into his inheritance.<br/><br/>He stood up, buttoning his tailored jacket. &quot;Gentlemen, welcome to the AGM. It's been another stellar year. Profits are up, turnover is up, market share is up in all sectors. Everything beyond expectations. The details are in the yearly reports that are beaming to your devices and to the social media corporations right now.&quot; On the wall, a ticker graph showed the company's share price rocketing, as the news spread.<br/><br/>&quot;Sadly, and this part is embargoed until we can talk to them, our partnership with Imperium must come to an end. The agreement to maintain a monopoly over access to local space was highly profitable, but our analysts have them reacting negatively to their exclusion from the Pandora project. Jens, can you give them the stats?&quot;<br/><br/>A gray-suited underling stepped forward, reading off a tab. &quot;Our projections have this negatively affecting Solar System profits in the region of 9-17% for the indefinite future. We've also incurred significant costs in bolstering security at our settlements, taking another couple of percent off this year's top line. Our fire teams are never going to be the quality of Imperium's troops, especially not their ‘300' assault squads, but the fixed emplacements at major bases should prevent any violent repercussions from the termination of the deal.&quot; He stepped back, almost blending into the wall.<br/><br/>Preston nodded his thanks, and continued. &quot;However, we're still the dominant economic entity in the solar system. We still have access to the cheapest Earth-to-orbit tech, the cheapest, best-designed ships thanks to our own shipyards, and an effective monopoly on ore extraction. Imperium won't dare offend us. They can't afford to.&quot;<br/><br/><style name='Heading'/>Callisto Station, the Asteroid Belt.<br/><style name='Default'/>Darin's light spacesloop swept into the shadow of the lead transporter, #2800. The ship was a great framework of interlaced steel, a fine strong cage built atop a solid base to contain the pieces of steel packed inside, backed by weak sub-light engines. It loomed above his craft like a metal cliff as it interfaced with the airlock. Other security teams, hastily scrambled, were attaching their sloops to the rear of the three newer transporters, and cautiously entering the cavernous interiors.<br/><br/>The transport driver greeted him and his team at the airlock, stinking of months trapped in his tiny cab at the front of the leviathan transport. &quot;Glad to see a face in the flesh!&quot; he said, &quot;I thought the handling was a little off, but I can't work out why she's bellying around. Come and look at the cargo.&quot; He led Darin to the great central chamber.<br/><br/>Darin inspected the cargo perfunctorily, scanning it with a handheld device. It was all accounted for, endless stacks of inert steel, no life signs, nothing. It just appeared to be overweight. Over his headset, the other teams reported the same thing. &quot;Return to base.&quot; he commed to the team-leaders. &quot;They must have been overloaded at Ceres.&quot; He turned to the trucker, with a second thought. &quot;It's going to slow completion, but I'm going to quarantine you four out here. My job is to prevent anything suspicious coming through the perimeter.&quot; The trucker nodded.<br/><br/>Darin's sloop headed back to the security station, bellying a little. On its underside, four soldiers of the Imperium's 300 division clung on with magnetic gloves, waiting for their moment.<br/><br/><style name='Heading'/>Noxium Headquarters, Earth.<br/><style name='Default'/>&quot;So we're agreed? Buy options on the company before dumping its stock. Good. Next on the-&quot;<br/><br/>The intercom buzzed. &quot;Sir, I know we have orders not to disturb you, but Admiral Heid is on Line 4 and is rather insistent.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Heid? Hmm. I guess we'd better get this done. In the meantime, execute plan IA3 -- you should find the details in my private folder, password @3Headhunter -- and put him through.&quot;<br/><br/>The windows opaqued and the young face of James Heid appeared on them. &quot;Hello Eric, hello gentlemen. Apologies for interrupting your AGM.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;It's no imposition, James. I was half-expecting you to call. What can we do for you?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Well, it's a simple request really. We at Imperium have appreciated working with you over the past fifty years, but we're a little concerned. We've heard that you're working with Togra and Solar to design ships to travel to the newly discovered planet --&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;-- yes, Nashira 667 Cc. We're calling it Pandora.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;To Pandora, then, and that you've finished your prototype ship. Congratulations for that. So we wondered if our mutual co-operation was going to extend to Pandora as well?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Ah, yes. We did want to talk to you about that James. Frankly, we don't think we'll need your security services on this new world -- we're focusing on taking infrastructure-building groups rather than, ah, less-productive groups. But we fully intend to maintain the Ceres Cartel in this Solar System.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Eric, you know as well as I do that none of our groups has a future in this Solar System. The Earth may be uninhabitable soon and even Mars is far beyond the reach of our current terraforming tech. We need to move to Pandora and we need your ships to get there. Is it worth my asking again? I'm not going to beg.<br/><br/>&quot;James, you're a friend and I respect you, but this is a purely commercial decision. We can't sell you a ship. I'm sorry.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;In that case, I'm afraid to say that the Ceres Cartel is at end. We'll see you on Pandora.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;James, don't be ridiculous. You can't get there. We're building the ships to get to Pandora and I'm -- we're not selling you one.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Oh, we know that. So we just took one. Look.&quot;<br/><br/>The camera panned back to reveal Heid in full spacer's gear. Behind him, a line of Noxium Construction employees were kneeling on the ground, hands behind their heads, whilst a group of the Imperium 300 aimed lance rifles at their heads. And beyond them, wheeling in the vacuum, heading away from Callisto's docks, was the prototype interstellar ship, The Player of Games, now quite obviously under Heid's control.<br/><br/>Heid waved at the camera. &quot;Heid out.&quot; The image died.<br/><br/>The board was silent for a beat, then uproar. Everyone was shouting at once. Preston sat still at the table's end, his pale face impassive. The ticker on the wall showed the Noxium stocks in freefall.<br/><br/>&quot;Gentlemen. Gentlemen!&quot; he said. &quot;GENTLEMEN.&quot; The room quieted. &quot;Watch the screen.&quot; As the board turned to watch, the ticker stabilised and cautiously recovered. The room grew noisy again, this time with puzzlement. Preston explained. &quot;When our friend Heid called, I suspected the game was up, so triggered plan IA3. I had my subsidiaries bet the farm that our stock would drop after the AGM. By the looks of things, that bet covered our loss on the prototype ship, the costs of another ship and gave us a nice bonus on top. Now, to work, gentlemen. We've got a world to buy.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="2Name" value="The Callisto Conflict"/>
	<entry name="3Description" value="A small, bustling figure, bowed under a great stack of papers, ushered six men into the long windowless boardroom. Here, deep beneath the Solar Dynasty's City Number 1, in a reinforced meeting room proof against anything but the still- theoretical black hole bombs, the Solar Dynasty's nominal Standing Committee met.<br/><br/>The stern, upright men sat down in leatherette chairs around the table. Looking around their faces, though they were all of different ages, the resemblance was more than merely familial. These were six clones of the late President of the People's Republic, Sheng Xi. Young or old, slender or rotund, they owed their place on Standing Committee of the Politburo, and their lives, to Xi's genetic line.<br/><br/>At the table's end, the bent secretary deposited the great heap of papers with a dusty thump on a placemat, sat down on a low stool, coughed, leaned around the pile for a glass of water, and spoke.<br/><br/>&quot;Congratulations, Comrades one and all, on your elevation to the Central Standing Committee of the Politburo of the Solar Dynasty unified party. Your clone-father, may his works never fail, stipulated that only those who bore his genetic line could rise to this position for reasons of state security. Those of us who are born outside his blessed line can only work for the good of all under your direction.&quot;<br/><br/>A worn-looking, heavily-built clone interrupted. &quot;I am Xilai Xi, newly appointed Deputy Party secretary of the State Council of the People's Republic of China. Secretary, you are not our chairman. Where is our chairman?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Ah, yes. That is the first point on our agenda. I have to regret to inform you that intelligence came to light of a counter-revolutionary element in the newly-elected politburo Central Standing Committee.&quot; The men around the table murmured their disquiet. &quot;It would not be wise for a role as valuable as the chairman to expose himself to such risk. And anyway, he is currently being interrogated. Instead, I, as your secretary, am here to ensure that the traitor is found as quickly as possible. I have a squad of revolutionary guard outside, awaiting my signal.&quot;<br/><br/>Another aged clone interrupted, his round bland face carefully communicating irritation. &quot;Secretary, I am Xi Dejang, Secretary of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Traitors are my field, my remit. Why was I not informed of this beforehand?&quot;<br/><br/>The secretary bowed his head, servile. &quot;Because you yourself are suspect, and the Chairman so ordered it, before his own corruption was discovered. My apologies. Now, to business. Until I can guarantee which of you is the traitor, we will remain here. Does anyone have any information to share?&quot;<br/><br/>The six men looked around the room. Lives spent in the morass of party intrigue had hardened each of them but, still, it was a psychological blow to be so accused at their triumphal moment. Each of the six scanned the room for weakness, racked their memories as to who might be the traitor -- or traitors.<br/><br/>A moment. Another. The secretary cleared his throat. &quot;So, no ideas? Not one. Let me prompt you. Hmm. Zhang Xi. You are party secretary of the National Committee of the People's Political Consultative Conference. As the head of our advisory legislature, you must be aware of dissent in the ranks?&quot;<br/><br/>Zhang, a older clone with a face lined from smiling and scowling, seemed distressed. &quot;I know of no such dissent!&quot; he barked. &quot;The legislature is free of counter-revolutionaries. &quot;<br/><br/>The secretary looked down, playing with a pencil. &quot;And yet there is dissent,&quot; he said &quot;according to this report from the Discipline Inspection commission headed by... hmm, Xi Dejang? So who is the traitor?&quot; The two older clones glared at each other across the table, instant enemies. And the secretary smiled.<br/><br/>---<br/><br/>An hour later, and the calm, smug atmosphere of the room had transformed. From the secretary's gentle prompting, each of the men had accused every single other, with old secrets or shared crimes or allegations of counter-revolutionary intent or simply flung dirt, and the room was a raging, ongoing row.<br/><br/>Gradually, the storm of accusations abated. Silence fell as the clones realised one after another that the secretary was himself silent. They watched in horror as he continued to transcribe the litany of their crimes on his great stack of paper. Eventually, he noticed their gaze. &quot;Ah, comrades. So much material. So much misery, so many covered-up failures. Our dear clone- father would be quite proud of you -- you have followed in his misdemeanours so very well.&quot;<br/><br/>He pressed a buzzer and ranks of masked, armed soldiers filed into the room. &quot;Now, comrades. You had better follow these men out, as the interrogators have some questions for you. Don't worry, I am quite capable of carrying out this agenda by myself. Goodbye.&quot; In silence and humiliation, the six clones trudged out.<br/><br/>&quot;Now, Yun Xi&quot; said the little secretary to himself. &quot;It appears the next item on the agenda is the election of a Prime Minister for the Solar Dynasty. How does everyone vote?&quot; He looked around the empty room and leatherette chairs, amusing himself. &quot;Oh, my. It seems we have a draw. Well, in the sad absence of this committee's chairman who should have the casting vote, it appears the secretary must decide. Now, who should I vote for? Hmm.&quot; Pulling a ballot paper out of his stack, he bent low to write a name into a box.<br/><br/>---<br/><br/>Across the fields, mines and factories, the traditional three- chord tone blared, announcing important news. The people looked up, half with weariness, half with interest. &quot;TO THE DELIGHT OF THE PEOPLE AND THE JOY OF OUR BLESSED, LATE LEADER SHENG XI, HIS CHERISHED SON YUN XI HAS BEEN ELECTED PRIME MINISTER TO THE PEOPLE. ALL HAIL YUN XI, LEADER OF THE SOLAR DYNASTY.&quot;<br/><br/>In the fields, they hardly felt the change."/>
	<entry name="3Name" value="Bring On The Clones"/>
	<entry name="4Description" value="The children were huddled in the glow of the campfire. They sneaked adoring looks at the old, old lady (&quot;Maybe as old as 40!&quot; they'd whispered to one another) who was tonight's storyteller. She settled her old bones near the warmth and cleared her throat.<br/><br/>&quot;Are you all sitting comfortably? Then I'll begin.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;A long, long time ago, on a planet far, far away, there was a country called Brazil. And there Elora, mother of Vivian, was born.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;One day a lot of men looked up at the sky and they saw a new star. Using things called tellys and scopes they looked closer at it and they grew hungry. For these weren't men like your dads.<br/><br/>These were Eaters, men who just had to eat everything they came across, and leave a mess everywhere they went.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;They'd already made a mess of their planet, which they called Earth. They'd eaten all the trees and all the animals and all the water out of all the taps and they'd started turning the stone and dirt into food too. Pretty much all that was left to eat was the brave little fungus that would live anywhere; and maybe each other. ...and they'd really started to get bored of fungus.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;So, when they saw the star they wanted it, and they wanted to eat everything on it. Now, I don't want to scare you, but that star was here! It was our home, Pandora! And they wanted to come here to eat everything until it was just like Earth. So they built themselves huge boats to carry them through space, and they packed all their best knives and forks.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Luckily, not all the people were like those Eaters. Some of them, like Elora, heard what the men were up to and made a plan. Using scraped together old bits and their cleverness and their desperation to save Pandora's life, they built themselves a boat just like the Eaters, and followed them through the long dark.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;But there were problems with the boat. Because it had been built so fast and from so many strange parts, it wasn't a very strong or large boat, though it was a VERY brave boat. So, up there in the long dark it started to fall apart; some of the dark started coming in through the planks of the boat.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Now, the families on the ship, led by Elora, had to make a decision. A lot of food had been spoiled by the darkness, and some people had been made sick by it. The decision was that all the young people would be protected and that the older people, like Elora, would keep the ship running.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;So by the time the boat finally landed on Pandora there were very few old people left. They'd all worked so hard and used up so much of their life to protect the children that they were all sick with the darkness. So the remaining few pretty much let the children take over.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;The oldest of the children was Elora's daughter Vivian. So when they landed she said to the other children, &quot;You stay here and help the oldies get to sleep. I'm going to go and warn all the things that live here about the Eaters.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Vivian went out into Pandora. And it was beautiful. There were great mountains and green trees and a blue sea so clear and clean you could see all the way to the bottom of it! She loved it on sight and swore that she would do her best to protect it from the Eaters, no matter what.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;First she went to the Scites. They buzzed like great fairies around her and listened quietly to her. &quot;Listen&quot; she said. &quot;The Eaters are coming and they eat everything. They ate The Earth and they'll eat you too!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;The Scites were frightened but their leader, the monstrous Devourer, boomed out in his great voice. &quot;We can fly high -- oh- so-high -- that even the tall Galeth can't reach us. So how will these Eaters?&quot; So Vivian left them, happy they were safe.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Then she went to the Bugs to warn them. The bugs had never seen a human before so scratched around her with their giant claws and stared with their jewel-like eyes. When they saw she wasn't scared they let her visit their Queen. The Queen was sat in all finery on a great throne in her egg-chamber, and listened to Vivian. &quot;Listen&quot; Vivian said. &quot;The Eaters are coming and they eat everything. They ate The Earth and they'll eat you too!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;The bugs all shook as one, because they all have only one mind after all, but then the Queen stamped her feet and shook her great head, and said &quot;The Eaters won't eat us. There are too many of us to eat, millions and millions. And we won't let them.&quot; So Vivian left them, happy they were safe.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Then Vivian went to find the Aspidoch. She knew the Aspidoch was the oldest and wisest creature alive on the planet, and that he might listen to her. She travelled for weeks, sailing out into the centre of the crystal ocean until she saw what looked like an island on the horizon. It was the Aspidoch, sunbathing. She walked a mile up his belly to an earhole like a cave mouth and shouted. &quot;Listen&quot; she said. &quot;The Eaters are coming and they eat everything. They ate The Earth and they'll eat you too!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;But&quot; the Aspidoch said, &quot;They won't eat me. I'll swim away. If they follow me, I'll flatten them. And, anyway, there's just too much of me to eat.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Vivian went home, reassured that her friends were going to be alright. When she got home, the last of the oldies had died. So they buried them in the gardens alongside her mother Elora and then she helped the other shipchildren build a paradise on Pandora.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Then there was a great flapping in the air. It was the proud Devourer, his great wings now all tattered and torn. &quot;The Eaters have come!&quot; he said, &quot;and they're eating all my friends. They have guns which can reach us wherever we fly! Help!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Before Vivian could answer, there was a great skittering and the Bug Queen arrived, borne aloft by her children, her chitin chiton in rags. &quot;The Eaters have come!&quot; she said, &quot;and they're eating all my children. They have tanks and robots to roll us into pancakes by the million! Help!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Before Vivian could answer either of them, a giant Galeth came galumphing over the hill. &quot;The Eaters have come!&quot; he said, &quot;and the Aspidoch is hiding. They have boats and planes to find him, and the biggest knives and forks I've ever seen! If you don't come soon, they're sure to eat him up like a big plum pudding! Help!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;And that's the story. That's where we are now. And the Eaters call themselves all sorts of names -- Solo Dynasty, Imperious, Toga, Noxious and Devious Ascension -- but they're Eaters all the same. If we don't help Vivian and our friends, there won't be anyone left, and the Eaters will eat everything.&quot;<br/><br/>There was silence round the campfire. One child burst into huge sobs. Another, slightly older, raised her voice, angry and tearful. &quot;That was a RUBBISH story! Stories are meant to have happy endings. It should have been ‘and then they all lived happily ever after' not-&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;What?&quot; interrupted the old lady. &quot;Happy endings aren't free. You have to fight for them. And it was a true story! I'm Vivian. And I do need your help.&quot;"/>
	<entry name="4Name" value="How The Eaters Came To Pandora"/>
	<entry name="5Description" value="&quot;Sometimes, when you're crying, the world just jumps into focus. The water in your eyes wells up enough that a kind of lens forms and everything just sharpens and makes sense. The sobs, the alien walls, the blood on your hands. They all just sort of -- jump -- and then it's all right. It fits. I mean, you're still going to die, but you don't mind so much any more.&quot;<br/><br/>Field-researcher Andrez stopped there, looked around and beamed proudly. There was a perplexed murmur from the assembled Ops team.<br/><br/>&quot;What the FRAK?&quot; yelled Hughes afterwards, as they walked out of the tent that was attached to the command ATV. &quot;What the FRAK was that?&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;That, Hughie, was a motivational speech from our commander&quot;, replied Abernathy, pursing her lips. &quot;That is what happens when the only survivor from your only archaeological expedition on the only alien world you've ever been to has come back a few claws short of a Galeth and you need someone to command the next, presumably equally-doomed mission.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;FRAKKING FRAKKERS!!&quot; yelled Hughes, kicking out at a passive alien plant in frustration. It dodged preternaturally fast and grabbed one of his bootlaces with a spiked pinion.<br/><br/>&quot;Think of it this way, Hughie.&quot; said Abernathy, &quot;At least he knows what we're up against and he's not lying to us about it. We knew what we were signing up for -- the chance to see something no human has ever seen -- and probably to die in the process. If I recall, that was the deal with coming to Pandora in the first place.&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;Yeah, but how FRAKKING low are our chances with him in charge? Let GO, you little bugger!&quot; Hughes struggled to extricate his bootlace before it was slowly devoured by the tiny alien.<br/><br/>Abernathy pulled a folding scalpel from her pocket and, crouching, severed the bootlace, toppling the swearing Hughes into the dust. The miniature alien uprooted itself and scurried off rapidly with its prize.<br/><br/>As Abernathy helped Hughes up, she looked at the great twisted ruins around them. &quot;Hughie, old boy, my stochastic analysis is a bit rusty, but I don't think you can reduce any odds to below zero.&quot;<br/><br/>---<br/><br/>The ruins could have been anything: dining hall, power centre, hospital, playing field, signalling station or some more inconceivable function. Whatever they had been, they'd been carved out entirely by the same catastrophic energy that had destroyed every single ancient city on the planet and presumably wiped out the inhabitants.<br/><br/>Now these particular ruins formed a great hollow chamber, big enough to hold one of the colony ships that had brought the Togra researchers to Pandora. So large was it that the base of its distant walls dipped below the horizon before being lost in haze and shadow.<br/><br/>The Togra ATV convoy made its way through one of the great holes punctured in the sides of the structure, rolling over the artefact-rich rubble. The lead Seeker ATV held Andrez and his assistant Maçon, scanning the landscape for trouble. In the second ATV, Hughes crouched dourly over the wheel whilst Abernathy read the instruments and smoked her pipe. The third ATV held the female security team of thickset Baker and paranoid Legg-Hulme, and weaved to avoid every pothole. The final ATV, holding quiet Curie and messy Yaort was waiting at the chamber's entrance, monitoring the situation and ready to run to a safe distance at any sign of trouble. That final team's job was just to ensure someone, anyone, survived.<br/><br/>The target of the convoy was a distant cluster of low buildings that had somehow survived the energies that carved the chamber. The three vehicles pushed on through the dust.<br/><br/>An hour later, the team was on foot. Back in the dust, where the buildings began, the lead ATV was in two smoking halves, having triggered some revenant defence system on approach. Maçon hadn't made it out and the gore-spattered Andrez had decided they should continue on foot. Baker was on point, toting a modified rifle of her own design. Hughes, Andrez and Abernathy were in the middle lugging analytics, medical and early-warning equipment. Behind them, Legg-Hulme was muttering nervously, covered in a range of homemade bombs and waving a pocket shotgun.<br/><br/>There was a chittering in the air. A shadow moved on a rooftop, disturbed dust blew between distant buildings. The team was definitely not alone, and it was getting closer to the centre of the ruins. Here stood something like a tall shard of glass, its translucency abraded by generations of diamond dust.<br/><br/>Time passed. As they neared a pulsating man-sized egg, Legg- Hulme's homemade bombs seemed to pulse twice in sympathy. She had time to stare down horrified, before they detonated, scattering her over the cowering Hughes and Abernathy. There was a silence. Andrez looked at the mess and, bending, took her battered shotgun. &quot;Sad. No time for burials. Press on.&quot;<br/><br/>An interminable trudge through diamond favelas later, a distant explosion echoed off the chamber's walls. Abernathy radioed Yaort and Curie, but there was no response on any frequency. Andrez was impassive. &quot;Dump the radio.&quot; he said. &quot;And the other gear. Need to be faster.&quot;<br/><br/>At the next building, Baker poked her gun around a corner, only for the barrel to dissolve, sizzingly as it encountered some strange energy field. &quot;Back&quot; said Andrez. They backtracked to make their way around the field, tossing small stones to find its boundaries.<br/><br/>Finally, four hours into the trek, they reached the tower. &quot;Slow now.&quot; said Andrez. It had an obvious doorway, much wider and lower than a man, but open. Baker, on point, bounded up to the side of the entrance, Andrez close behind.<br/><br/>There was a noise like creaking floorboards and Baker just... disappeared, seemingly falling sideways into a crack in the air that shouldn't have been there, before something detonates. Hughes and Abernathy are blasted into the tower. Abernathy is first to her feet. She can see Andrez kneeling in the dust outside the diamond tower, facing away from her. &quot;Go on&quot; he yells. &quot;Baker is gone. Boobytrap. Seems to have cauterised my eyes. Can't even cry now. Ha! GO ON.&quot;<br/><br/>Abernathy doesn't need another order and hauls Hughes's battered body up a slope inside the structure. &quot;Just think, Hughie.&quot; she chatters, trying to drown Andrez's grim laughter. &quot;If we both survive this, we'll have doubled the maximum survival stats for exploratory missions. We might get tenure!&quot; Hughes groans in response, &quot;We're already frakking dea-&quot; then stops as his handheld analytics gear starts twittering. &quot;What's this? Power surges in the building. Let me down. Let go!&quot;<br/><br/>Hughe's gear tracks the surges to a diamond wall like any other, which lights as the heat of his breath hits it. He breathes harder. The diamond tower above them peels away like sellotape, as does the ceiling above it. A light pours out from the buildings, is focused by the diamond shard, burns past the huddled figures, a beam focused on a particular distant star. Down in the dust, eyeless Andrez is shouting that he can see the light.<br/><br/>As fast as it starts, it cuts off. And then back on. In the dark moments, in the gap in the ruined ceiling, something is flashing faintly back from the stars, across impossible distances.<br/><br/>Abernathy sighs and relaxes. &quot;No more shilly-shallying, Hughie. It's got to be a beacon. And we've lit it!&quot;<br/><br/>&quot;We have. But I wonder... who's coming?&quot;<br/><br/>Abernathy looks around, frowning. Heaves Hughes to his feet. &quot;Let's not wait around here to find out, hey? I think we've done enough exploring today.&quot; They shambled off in search of Andrez and a safe route back to the ATVs."/>
	<entry name="5Name" value="For The Sake Of Science"/>
	<entry name="Count" value="6"/>
</language>
